If you want to insure any commercial vehicle, that is, the
vehicle whose number plate is yellow,
then you
can do it from your mobile within minutes. In today's
video, I will tell you in detail,
so watch this video carefully, you will also know
how much your commercial vehicle's insurance will cost.
Also, if
you feel it is right, you can complete the
insurance process yourself from your mobile online
and can also
get your Polo copy immediately.
So, how to do it, I will explain everything in this video,
so let's start. So, yes
everyone, my name is Vijay and you are watching
Vijay Solution, so first of all let me tell you
where to get the link for insurance,
what you have to do for that.
Suppose you are watching our video, then
you will see here below, you will
get an option of comment, if you click on this comment, then
you will get this link, so you will get this
link here,
what you have to do is simply click on it, as
soon as you click on it, this
website will open, so in this way
you will get the link as to where to get the
insurance, you can do it from somewhere else.
You will have to search and if you have any
issue then you have to do a simple
comment given below the video, you can simply click from here on
your mobile,
you will click on it, it will open in this way,
now you can see
here that the vehicle number is being asked here, so
whatever your vehicle number is, no matter which
vehicle it is, you have to enter that vehicle number here,
I have entered a vehicle number
here, so in the same way
whatever your vehicle number is, you have to enter it here
and after doing this click on search, as soon as
you click on search,
it will automatically take the details of this vehicle from its data, you
can see that it has
taken it automatically and if you look here then it will be
automatically selected in blue, so
you have to select the simple one which is selected in blue, do
not select anyone else,
if many times it selects wrong in your vehicle, then
you can see whatever is there of your vehicle
here, which
comes in commercial vehicle, pickup,
truck, auto rickshaw, all these
vehicles come, so you have to select everything here, pay
attention
You will not see the car insurance here, so
I have already made a separate video for the car on
our channel, so you can go there and
check it, if you do not find it, then you can
write Vijay solution for car insurance, then you will get it,
you will get all the other car insurance here, so you have to
select whichever vehicle you have, right now the vehicle number of which I am
entering is e-rickshaw, so automatic e-
rickshaw is selected, I will leave it here,
after that if you see,
automatic is written on the top, so if
you simply click on it, then the
automatic option will come, you have to select it,
after which you can see here that
this automatic is also selected,
so you have to keep clicking on all this simply,
after that it will come, then
you have to select it, so in
this way all the vehicle's insurance has been
selected, if you enter your vehicle number
and it does not come, then the
model number of your vehicle, variant number, all those
things, all those things which I have just selected here, all those things which  You have to
select them one by one and
after that the registration date is being said here,
it is written on the RC,
so you have to select the year of your vehicle
here and after that you have to
select the month
in which you bought the vehicle and
after that you have to select the date, in this
way your registration date will appear,
this registration date is
written on your RC, you have to enter it after checking it from there, you should
not enter it wrong, you have to select the
manufacturing date from here, so you have to
select the year whichever year it is and after that you have to
select the month, which year both these
things are written in your RC
and after that you have to click on submit,
after which because we had
entered the vehicle number, see it is automatically
written as RJ 14, so I will
select this one and after that it is being
said here that when did your last policy
expire, you have to tell that if you do
not remember your policy because there are many
All people forget, so such people have to
choose the option given here 'Previous Year Policy Not Available', we know that, that is why
I select the 14th date,
after that it is being asked whether you had taken
any kind of claim from the previous insurance company,
if you had taken it, then select yes, otherwise
select no and after that
yours will come in this manner, so you
can see here that it has come in this manner,
two plans are shown here in which it is
third party, in which also it is written in this manner,
understand that it is a third party
and if the money is written in this manner, it
means that the company has paid the price of the vehicle, then at that
time it is not the first
party, for those who do not know
what a third party is and
what a first party is, then I will explain the difference between these two,
if you take a third party
then the police will not fine you
anywhere, apart from this, if your
vehicle causes any loss to any other person
or any kind of loss occurs due to an
accident, then the insurance
company compensates for it, but the loss that you incur will also be
compensated.  The insurance company will not do it
if you take third party, then it means that
in third party and first party, you will
also get the claim, if someone else gets harmed by your vehicle,
he will also get the claim, so overall, we
can say that if you
take comprehensive, which is called first party, then
you will get it for everyone, that is,
first party and second, it is an all-in-one thing,
so you can decide
which one you want, there is a slight difference in money between the two, it
depends on you, so
let me tell you the rest of the things, so
here you can see that the
rate of third party is mentioned here and
this rate of first party is mentioned, in this
way you will get to know
how much the vehicle you want to insure will cost,
now I will
tell you some more things in this, like many people
want zero depth, apart from this, many
people want personal accident cover, they want
insurance for the passenger, if they want this type, then
how can you add it
in this, I will tell you because what has been
shown right now is of normal insurance in
which you  There won't be any problem,
but all these things that I have just mentioned are
not adds, so if you want to add them,
I will tell you how to do it.
What you have to do for that, you will get the option of
add-on right here, this one that you are seeing,
click on it and here
you will get the option of IMT, zero
depreciation of the car owner's
PA cover, apart from this there is
cover for the driver, so you get all these things here,
now suppose you
want zero definition or IMT, whatever you
want, you select it here and
suppose if we do it for the owner-driver, then there is
insurance of Rs. 15 lakh only,
so I have selected these two things
and after that I click on submit, then you will
see here that some rate will increase,
so here you can see that the PA cover has been added
but zero depreciation is
not included in it, it means that there cannot be
zero depreciation on this car, it
means that zero depth will not be there here, so in
this way you can see it
If you are getting it, then the way there
is a tick mark on this, similarly there will be a
tick mark on this also, if you do not want it, then
you can remove it from here, there is no problem with this
and I have removed both of them and it
depends on you whether you want it or
not and after that you have to click on submit, then the
plus button given here, on that
you will get all the options, whether it is for the owner or for the
passenger, everything, you
get the option there, tick whatever you want
and it will show you how much it will cost,
if you do not want it, then do not
add it as normal, let it remain like
I have done it now, then it has come as normal,
now whatever we want from this, I can
take it here, if you look here at the top, there are
some details like suppose
this is NCB, that means no claim bonus, when you do
not take any kind of claim from the previous insurance company, then you are given the benefit of NCB,
those are the things, if
you look in the previous insurance, then
whatever percentage is there, you will select that percentage here,
it will automatically increase a little.  It will
show you that it increases by 5. Here
you can see that the value of the vehicle is currently at the minimum, it is at the
lowest.
Suppose this is the value of the vehicle right now,
if you insure it, then if the
vehicle gets lost, then the insurance
company will give only ₹ 3000. But if you
want that the value of our vehicle
is more, then you can increase it from here,
which I have increased and now when
I update it, you can see here
that now it has gone up to ₹ 66000. So in
this way, you can also
increase the value of your vehicle here.
Now suppose if you want to
insure it, then you have to click on this.
If you want to do third party insurance, then you have to
click on third party. Let's
assume that only the first party
option is given here. If I do this, then for that
I click on it,
after which it is being asked whether
your previous policy is from United India,
meaning that if your previous
insurance would be from the same company, which is here  It is
showing here, like it is showing for United,
if there is previous insurance in United, then
this year we cannot do it in United, so of course they do
not have it, so
I am selecting No here,
after that it is being asked
how much is the NCB of last year, so as I told you,
NCB is written, so you have to check it from your previous insurance,
and if you do
not have previous insurance or it must have failed
or you do not know, then you select the % here, so
let me select 25 here, if I
select it, I will
get 35, if I select 20, I will get 25, if I select
zero, I will get 20, so this is
how NCB is done, you select yours here, the
rest the insurance
company will fix it itself, so suppose it is
25, then I select 25
and click on Confirm and Proceed,
after which it will
open in this manner, whatever
name is there, that is, whatever name the vehicle is in whose name,
you have to write it here.  Well,
you already write it
here, whatever your
email ID is, it is here,
after doing this you have to give your communication address
here,
I am just telling you people, that is why I am doing this,
but you people will
write your complete address here which will be written in the RC,
after that all these
details will appear below, if not then you have to
write all these things, your state, city and pin code, after that you have to come down
and click here and
click on next, after which it will
appear something like this, here your vehicle
number will be there, whatever it is, you have to check that there is
no mistake, if you
see the vehicle number correct here, then you have to
come down where it automatically takes your engine number,
if it is
not automatically selected then you have to
write your engine number here,
whatever the chest number is,
you have to write it here, the registration date
also has to be checked that there is no mistake, the
previous policy number is being asked
here  But a lot of people face problem,
you can get the previous policy number, I have already
made a video on that, so
you can go there and check it out,
if you have a lot of problem then
you can send me the vehicle number, I will tell you the
policy number, insurance company and all the
things, so let me
write down a policy number like this, I have
written the number like this, it is being said here
that your previous policy, comprehensive
or third party, whatever it is, you have to
select it here and here you have to
select which company the previous policy is from, so there is a lot of list here,
whichever company you have, you have to select it, it is being
said here that if your
RC has been transferred in 12 months, like
people buy an old car, then normally they get it
transferred, if they have got such a
transfer done then you have to answer it in yes or no,
after that here you are being
asked for loan, if you have a loan on your vehicle then select
yes and if not then
select no, if you say yes, then here you will be told
from which company you have taken the loan  If you have to
tell me, then whatever A B CD
company it is, you have to write the name of that company here.
If it is not there then
select no and after that click on next step.
After which
KYC is required here. Without KYC,
you will not be able to take the policy. So I will
tell you how to do KYC. And if you are
not able to do it, then how can you contact me
so that I can do it for you.
I will also tell you that. First, I will
tell you how to do it. If you are not able to do it, then
contact me and I will do it for you. So,
suppose you have to write your PAN card number
here. Here
you have to provide your date of birth in the PAN card. For that, you have to
select the year in which you were born.
After selecting the year, you have to enter the month here in this
manner. If it is there then it is
fine, otherwise you can proceed from here.
So I am going ahead in this manner.
Here I have come to this month and
select the date. In this way, our
date of birth has come. Now we  If I
click on verify, it will be verified. You have to be
careful here. Sometimes it only
asks for PAN card. Sometimes you will get
other options here like
doing it through document, so you can do it through any medium, there is
no problem. Then if
you face any problem, what you have to do is
simply click on it from the top. As soon as you
click, you will get an option here,
it is for copy. You have to
simply copy it on this and this
link which I have
[laughs]
whatsappwap.in details will come up. You have to
cross check everything once. There should not be any kind
of mistake in all of this. If all the
details given to you in this, like this
star, are correct, you also just
compare the things in the middle. If you find everything correct, then
what you have to do is simply, you will
see the option of Secure Link at the bottom. You have to click on it,
after which something like this will
come up here.
Suppose if you have an F P,
that's all for now in this video.
Thank you very much.